[relaxing music]
[grunts]
[EMILIA] Subaru.
What's wrong?
I've just got some nerves.
Well, considering where
we're headed to, you know?
Of course.
Ram and Rem are coming
with us this time.
Not to mention,
we'll have Meili,
and our guide, Ms. Anastasia.
Please know I'm also
here to keep you safe.
Wait, what?
You're really lumping
me in with the people
who need protecting?
[growling]
[MEILI] Oh, dear.
I don't think these two like
the mabeast smell I have
on me very much, I'm afraid.
Hey, you can't
do that, Joseph.
Let her go.
What a good boy.
Gently stroking
the neck like this
has a calming effect
on most land dragons.
Oh, really?
Let's see.
That true, Patrasche?
Guess it doesn't always work.
So, uh, whatever you do, be
sure not to leave me alone
with that one, all right?
Otherwise, I might
just get gobbled up.
Nothing that scary
is going to happen.
My Patrasche is a vegetarian.
[ROSWAAL] Subaru, Ms.
Emilia, there's something
about Ram you should know.
[SUBARU] Got it.
Do feel free to ask her
about the matter directly.
Beatrice can also
give you more details.
Don't worry.
We'll do everything we can
to give Ram our full support.
[FREDERICA] Master?
Both ladies are prepared
and ready for the journey now.
[ROSWAAL] Wonderful.
Ram, do practice caution
during your travels.
Thank you for granting me
my request, however selfish.
I swear, I'll
return with results
that meet your expectations.
Subaru-- I mean,
sir, be careful.
I will.
OK, Petra and Frederica, hold
down the fort while we're gone.
Yes.
You needn't even ask.
Right.
To Auguria Dunes.
Let's go.
[theme music]
♪ ♪
[wind blowing]
What can I get you?
Milk, please.
A cold one.
Same here.
Make mine hot.
[SUBARU] I get
the feeling business
isn't exactly booming here.
You must not get very many
customers during the sand time?
Yeah, this town doesn't have
a lot of outsiders
passing through as it is.
So, what are
the two of you doing
all the way out in Mirula,
during the sand time at that?
You see, we're going
to conquer the Auguria Dunes.
Some words of advice,
leave or you'll die.
Not an option.
There are some things that
you have to see through.
[sighs]
400.
It's been 400 years since
anyone's managed to reach it.
The dunes are
infested with mabeasts
and the witch's miasma.
You can walk forever and never
get any closer to that tower.
You'd be lucky
to make it back alive.
Most who've tried are still
out there, buried in the sand.
So, don't try, take my advice.
[EMILIA] I'm sorry.
I get it.
I can tell that
you really care for our safety.
I don't.
I'm just getting
sick and tired of it,
of watching young,
careless folks like you
make the same mistakes.
That's all.
[EMILIA] Thank you
for the drinks.
And thank you for being
open about all that, too.
You've been a big help.
Later.
[clanging]
I heard something
that might help you out.
The past year or so,
folks have been seeing
birds flying over the dunes.
The people who've seen
'em say the same thing,
no matter what, the birds
always seem to be
heading toward that tower.
So, if you do end up getting
lost, look to the sky.
If you're lucky, you might find
a guide to show you the way.
Mister.
Well, if you're already lost
out there with nowhere to turn,
I'd say your luck's
probably run out already.
[EMILIA] The Pleiades
Watchtower.
The home of that
powerful sage of legend.
[mysterious music]
How have your spirits
been acting since?
Mostly the same.
They still remain
by my side, as usual,
though they seem perplexed.
My divine protection of guiding
spirits seems to be intact.
Though at present, they
seem unsure why they find it
so difficult to leave my side.
So they've forgotten.
But the contract you
made hasn't been broken.
Basically, I can only
fulfill my duty as a knight
with my swordsmanship.
Without spirit arts
at my disposal,
my capacity has dropped
rather significantly.
I'm the one in this
predicament.
Why do you appear even
more vexed than I?
Don't you go making stuff up.
Why the hell would I
be the slightest bit
upset you've gotten weaker?
Who gave you that idea?
[JULIUS] You are less
suited to keeping secrets
than I had realized.
Heh, I believe I've come
to understand you more fully
through our travels together.
[SUBARU] Ha.
Well, same here.
If this keeps up
and nothing else happens,
I'm going to be a Julius expert
by the time we reach the tower.
Don't worry about that.
There's no doubt in my mind.
Aside from myself,
of course, there's
not a person in the world
who knows me better than you.
I had to go and get myself
stuck with that crappy title.
Damn.
Subaru, you can't
keep playing around
like that forever, I suppose.
The sand time is
about to start,
so we need to concentrate.
[whooshing]
[SUBARU] Hang
in there, Patrasche.
You too, Joseph.
We've got wind and miasma.
We need to watch out
for mabeasts, too.
Also, it's imperative that
we keep an eye on the tower
so we don't end up
lost, I suppose.
[SUBARU] I don't
know about that.
I feel like it'd be pretty hard
to lose sight of that thing.
[BEATRICE] Betty agrees
with your assessment,
but we must expect
the unexpected, I suppose.
The fact is, no one
has ever made it there,
so anything can happen.
[SUBARU] That is true.
Ms. Anastasia.
What's up?
You're sure
the best thing to do
is keep going straight ahead?
Oh, come on, why are you
acting so suspicious of
me, Natsuki?
We're all in the same
boat here, you know.
So you can be more trusting.
You're asking
him to trust a fox.
That's easier said
than done, I suppose.
Oh, you already told
her about me, did you?
I mean, wouldn't that
be OK with Ms. Anastasia?
You got that right, Natsuki.
You have no reason to worry.
I will keep my promise.
[SUBARU] And what
about you, Meili?
Are you doing your job?
Well, we haven't run into
even a single mabeast since we
got to the dunes, have we?
I mean, no.
But has that really
been your doing?
Oh, you doubt me?
Have it your way.
I'll show you just how much you
should appreciate me instead.
Huh?
[rumbling]
[roars]
[snaps]
[MEILI] There, all done.
What was that?
It was a sandworm, no doubt.
But still, I don't
recall there being
any record of one that large.
So?
Starting to see me
in a different light
now after that little show?
[gentle music]
♪ ♪
Oh, man, I'm dying to get
out of these damn dunes
and into a bathtub.
Right there with you.
Anyway, you two, you've
realized by now, surely.
Oh, yeah, I have.
We've been heading straight
for the tower this entire time.
[EMILIA] But we aren't
getting any closer to it.
Reinhard said he was
never able to make it there.
This must be why.
[ANASTASIA] It's
because the space
around here is warped.
[JULIUS] Hmm?
Uh, what do you
mean it's warped?
Basically, it might
seem like the dunes
and the tower are connected
with only sand between them,
but they're not.
In reality, it's
entirely possible
that we're just running
around in endless circles.
[JULIUS] I see.
Then that's what really
makes the Auguria Dunes
so incredibly dangerous.
It makes sense.
[SUBARU] So are
we going to end up
like the other
adventurers, overpowered
by this wibbly wobbly space?
We're different.
I volunteered to guide y'all
out to the Pleiades Watchtower
for a reason.
When a merchant heads out
to make a big purchase,
they're always heading
out to win, you know.
Then do you mean to say
that you're able to see
a clear path to the tower?
During the sand time,
when the wind picks up,
it's the recoil
from space twisting
and returning to normal.
In other words, the periods
between the sand times
are when the distortion
lets up, opening rifts.
And through those little
cracks is the real sea of sand
that's connected to the tower.
The real sea of sand, huh?
That's why it's a good
thing we have someone with us
with a special
ability that'll help
us find those pesky cracks.
[mysterious music]
[SUBARU] We need you to use
your clairvoyance to see
through the eyes of mabeasts.
If there are mabeasts that stay
active during the sand time,
surely some must be coming
through the cracks in
space somewhere.
I wonder if it's a sandworm.
[JULIUS] And to find
them, we have
Meili locate the mabeasts
with her ability
and tell Ms. Ram
where they are.
No good.
I've lost the connection
to that one.
Subaru, it isn't right to put
Ram through any more of this.
[RAM] Ms. Emilia.
We don't have another choice.
Only I can do this job.
It's my duty.
Meili, you can leave out the
mabeasts that are underground.
It's a waste of effort when
I can only see sand ahead.
I don't have a good handle
on telling them apart.
[RAM] Maybe you should
try harder instead of
giving up on them right away.
[MEILI] I really don't think
the idea in itself is wrong.
It's just a matter of catching
the right mabeast, I guess.
If we're going to be forced
to leave it up to luck,
I'm afraid we're
at a huge disadvantage.
It's a bird.
Can't believe
there's a bird that'd
want to fly through this sky.
A bird?
[EMILIA] Natsuki?
[suspenseful music]
Subaru, did you see one?
A ton.
Ram, are you able to see
through a bird's eyes?
Why are you asking?
[SUBARU] Those
birds are our key.
[squawking]
I'm connected.
Yes.
We're going to show
the sand time who's boss.
Let's go.
[exciting music]
Straight.
Keep going.
Please let this work.
Let this be it.
I don't want to put them
through any more.
Come on.
[thud]
[gasps]
We did it.
It's finally over.
It worked.
We really did it.
Hey, I'm right here.
Quit screaming
in my ears, I suppose.
Aw, no need to put
on airs with me.
You can celebrate.
Now, banzai.
I say, banzai, I suppose.
[SUBARU] Look at that.
It's proof we made it
to the next stage.
The dunes turned into
an endless field of flowers.
Field of flowers?
That's not right.
They're Oiran Bears.
[rumbling]
[growling]
Subaru, what's going on?
Ram's clairvoyance suddenly--
Stop.
Meili, stay calm.
Keep quiet.
[roars]
Shh.
Hey, don't move, OK?
[intense music]
[tutting]
[sighs]
[growls]
[roars]
No!
Go.
Now.
This is bad.
Why are they so fast?
Hey.
Yah!
Take that!
Take a whole bunch of 'em!
Oh, yeah.
That's my girl for you.
Barusu, if you want to live,
push her to the limit.
Don't worry,
I-- what was that?
[slashing sound]
It would be unseemly
of me to allow Ms. Emilia
to shoulder all of the work.
Damn, I can't
let him be better.
Beako, ready to do this?
Of course I am.
That's never a worry.
It's you who'd better not
run out of gas, I suppose.
Minya.
[shattering]
Go and give them all you've
got, my little sandworm.
Crush them all to dust!
Just a little further.
We've got to charge
straight for the watchtower.
Huh?
What?
[tutting]
I died and went back?
Why?
When?
What happened?
How did I die?
Shit, shit, shit,
shit, shit, shit.
[roars]
What?
No.
Julius!
[roars]
Damn.
Go, as fast as you can now.
[EMILIA] Take that.
Subaru.
Beatrice.
Minya.
[shattering]
[MEILI] I've got a present
for you-- my precious sandworm!
[rumbling]
Go!
Damn it.
Everything's going exactly
the same way as before.
Barusu, if you want to live,
push her to the limit.
Ram, don't head
for the tower yet.
We gotta find another route.
[RAM] What do you mean?
It's a straight line,
and there's no other way.
We can't go straight there.
We have to change direction.
Ram, do what Subaru says.
He would never blurt out
something nonsensical and silly
without a good reason.
Barusu speaks
nonsense and falsehoods
on a daily basis, though.
He would never blurt out
something nonsensical and silly
when we're obviously
in grave danger.
Thank you for the rephrase.
I really feel your support.
You two up top, don't let
yourselves get shaken off.
[roars]
Huh?
Dodge!
[rumbling]
[groans]
That was a close one.
Subaru, we messed up.
Huh?
We got separated from
Emilia's carriage, I suppose.
Now it's just you
and Betty out here.
What?
At this point, I'd take
fighting that bastard Regulus
again over figuring this out.
No time for whining
and complaining, I suppose.
We have to find a way back to--
Yeah, I know that.
I'm trying to think.
[slicing noise]
What just--
[groans]
Subaru.
No, you can't.
You can't die.
Don't you dare die.
Don't leave me all alone.
Don't-- don't you go
and leave Betty behind.
[explosion]
[tutting]
[mysterious music]
[SUBARU] The first and second
death were both from--
[grunts]
[heavy breathing]
Beako, I love you.
Huh?
[muffled gasp]
Invisible Providence.
What a good boy.
[grunts]
[SUBARU] There's something
I want to ask you guys.
Did anyone else see a flash
of light coming from the tower?
[EMILIA] Why, did
you see something?
[SUBARU] Yeah.
And this light, what
do you think it was?
I think probably
something dangerous.
Definitely not
friendly, at least.
Based only on a hunch?
Well, pretty much, yeah.
Ah, that's troubling.
But it's just a hunch.
You believe me?
It's your hunch, after all.
So it's a matter we
should take seriously.
Oh.
Ram?
It's Barasu that
it's watching.
[high pitched whistle]
I've got it!
[smashing noise]
[grunts]
Needle?
[RAM] Barusu, there's another.
Beako, are you ready?
Obviously.
EMT.
I suppose.
[swooshing]
[clangs]
What did you do?
Absolute nullification
magic, EMT.
When any magic reaches
this field surrounding us,
it sputters out in an instant.
The catch, it doesn't
last too long.
[rumbling]
What the?
We made a mistake.
It would seem the EMT we cast
is making the distortion
in space come undone.
I get it.
The sand time works
the exact same way
as Beako's door crossing.
[screaming]
[intense music]
[WOMAN] I found you.